Good Morning!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
Thank you. Have your seat.
Let's just dwell on the message we discontinued last Sunday.
Part 2 this time: Believe And Confess.
This actually relates to the reality of our daily life.
Let's take our reading to the Book of Matthew 12.
I will take my reading from verse 1; back to the proof text.
"At that time Jesus went through the grainfields on the Sabbath.
His disciples were hungry and began to pick some heads of grain and eat them.
When the Pharisees saw this, they said to him,
'Look! Your disciples are doing what is unlawful on the Sabbath.'"
Let's go to the proof text.
34.
"For the mouth speaks what the heart is full of."
That shows that the word we speak determines the life we enjoy.
If heart and mouth both get in accord with God's Word,
it means the word we speak determines the life.
But if they are not according to the truth of God's Word,
they will remain idle, meaningless and oftentimes destructive.
That is, the heart and mouth both get in accord with God's Word.
Last week, that Book of Romans 10 from verse 8 was our proof text.
What are we saying?
In a nutshell, we are saying, confession is part of salvation just as believing.
Confession is part of salvation just as believing.
Be a talking Christian, a reporting Christian, not only a doing one.
If you believe what you are doing, you will report.
If you believe what you are doing and hearing, you will report.
For you to be working and working - you are seeing the wrong around
and you decide not to say it or report it.
It means, you don't believe what you are doing.
Reporting should be an expression of believing
because if you believe in what you are doing, you will report.
If you believe in what you hear, you will report.
When we are expectant and you are given an assignment, "Oh, this is a job for you",
that job will not lead to success, unless you as well report;
at the same time you report the evil going on around.
We are expected to work as well as to report the wrong around
because when you are working without reporting, you are working in vain.
Working alone cannot help an establishment to grow.
Any establishment expects two things from you: working and reporting - for their growth.
That is why your company does not grow.
That is why our home is not in order.
When you report what you see, what you hear, it settles issues, it answers questions,
it provides a way forward, it clarifies doubt.
When you report what you see and hear, it settles issues.
A clear example is seen in Matthew 11:2-5 when John the Baptist sent his disciples
to clarify the identity of Jesus.
"Who is the man?"
And Jesus asked them to go and report to John what they had seen and heard.
Wherever you find yourself, you have to report what you see, what you hear.
You have to because work alone cannot help any establishment to grow.
That is why the companies do not grow.
You work; you see everyone working and working.
That cannot help the establishment to grow.
Establishment expects two things from you.
Working - everywhere working, working. No!
Working alone cannot help your family, your company, your ministry.
This is why Jesus said, go into the world and preach the Gospel.
What is the purpose of Emmanuel TV?
If not Emmanuel TV, you people would have clouded me here
and given me a name that Jesus has not given me.
You would have changed my name, if not Emmanuel TV.
That is reporter.
Say, "Good reporter".
Emmanuel TV - good reporter.
You can see everywhere - silent.
Emmanuel TV silenced them.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The pharisees and sadducees - this Emmanuel TV has silenced everyone.
When you are telling people, "This is white", they say, "No, we have seen it is yellow".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We have the mind of Christ.
1 Corinthians 2:16.
Don't be afraid to say you don't know if you don't.
Tell your neighbour.
Don't be afraid to say, "I don't know", if you don't know.
[Don't be afraid to say, "I don't know", if you don't know.]
Satan hates an independent mind - a mind that will think for itself,
a mind that is determined to find out the truth from God.
"No! What you are telling me, I need to pray over it."
Satan hates that heart.
"No, what you are telling me... Ok. I need to pray over it.
I need to know the truth from God." - Satan hates that.
Satan wants you to take everything you hear and see without questioning.
Everything - "Oh yes, it's right."
Satan wants us to take everything we hear and see without questioning.
That is satan; he hates an independent mind - a mind that will think for itself,
that will determine to find out the truth from God.
He hates it; that is satan for you.
I just want to prepare you for this week you are about to enter.
That is why I'm here.
Working and reporting scrutinizes the relationship among us.
If you know I'm a very good reporter, you will be very careful to come near me.
"You know this man - I know what you are going to say.
He will report every wrong thing he sees."
"Oh, this man!"
You will talk less; go there and say the truth.
Working and reporting scrutinizes the relationship among us.
If you are one that works as well as reports,
people will be very careful the way and manner they work and relate with you
because they know you will report anything wrong.
This will naturally select those who will relate with you.
Naturally.
For it is said, "Show me your friends and I will tell you whom you are".
What you are today is a result of your friends.
You cannot do it alone; you need good friends, informed and disciplined ones.
But where will you get these in the town around you?
Where are they?
The friends we have around today are dividing, subtracting.
You know what is happening to you.
To have the right friend, you have to be a good reporter.
You have to stand to report every wrong that is going on.
Let the people know that this man - "Hm... He will report anything around him.
Anything that is wrong, he will report it."
That is only saving grace to have a like mind.
When you want to employ people in your company, that is the first question.
This - I know you will work, I know you are a hard-working guy.
But as well, you must report every wrong that is going on.
If not, you have not worked, you have not done anything right.
We must work as well as report.
For example, the way and manner your colleagues behave in an establishment
must be reported to help the establishment grow.
Unruly behaviours of other employees must be reported to help the establishment grow
not just becoming a hard worker.
The devil can work.
As we are talking now, the devil is working.
When you see many of your friends that you love so much,
later you discover it is the devil - they are very hard-working people.
But this is what the devil will not do:
The devil will not come to you and say, "Excuse me, there is a man
that is in a pool of blood there. He needs help".
The devil will not say that.
The devil will not say, "Because you are a smoker, that is why you have this tuberculosis".
He wants you to smoke more - the devil will not report this.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So you have been here since morning.
What report do you have for me?
That is what we are saying.
But you want to receive miracle, deliverance, blessing
and at the end of the day, you do like this... - you are going.
You have been dancing since morning.
There are some funny men, funny women that are making noise, disturbing the group,
playing games on their set, playing games inside the church.
You see them and you know this is unruly behaviour.
If you don't report them, you are not here today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know some others, they have been moving from one group to another,
trying to make connections, sending a paper to groups.
You don't know what they have written but they keep sending it.
They are first-class beggars inside the church,
disturbing others that are here for the salvation of their souls.
It must be reported.
If this is in order, the world will be at its best, at peace.
You have to take this home.
Reporting should be an expression of believing.
Because you believe in what you are doing, you report.
Because you do not believe in what you are doing, you don't report.
You are here today; you have seen.
Your duty is to tell the world what you have seen!
Take time.
You can even move from one country to another -
"I just want to share what I have seen." You must be a good giver.
You are saved to save others.
You move, you take your time, any time you are back to your country.
Just take your time; you can fly from one city to another,
just to share what you have seen today with others.
Be a good reporter - first to God, then to men.
Rise up for prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whatever you have as a contact for your nation, please raise it up.
Let's pray for your nation.
God's intervention!
This is the voice of God!
Ask for God's intervention.
Ask God to intervene in your economics, in your politics.
God's intervention in the economies of your nations and politics of your nation -
God's intervention!
Open your lips!
Ask God to intervene!
The right hand of God is power!
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Ask God to redeem your leaders - wisdom and understanding.
God's intervention, in Jesus Christ's name we pray!
I can't hear you!
[Amen!]
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Thank You, Lord.
Let us strengthen you for your journey back home.
Open your lips.
Ask God to strengthen you in your journey back home -
journey of righteousness and uprightness.
Strengthen me, Lord!
Put in me Your right attitude!
Put in our hearts Your right attitude!
Prayer!
Prayer For The Nations
With Prophet T.B. Joshua
I surrender all
All to Thee my blessed Saviour
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is need for you to surrender.
When you reflect on God's mercy to you, His mercy is unlimited.
Reflect on God's mercy to you - God's mercy on us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Mercies and glory
And honour and praise
Be unto Christ our Lord
In Jesus Christ's name we pray!
I can't hear your "Amen!"
[Amen!]
Don't forget the summary of the message:
Every establishment, company, ministry expects two things from you -
work and report.
You are going now.
Think of the report you have before you leave.
You have to look at whatever that is not right -
you are to report it.
In your company, everywhere.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you are looking for perfection, go to Heaven.
That is why there is need for report.
You need to go to Heaven to see perfection.
Be a good reporter.
Tell your neighbour.
[Be a good reporter.]
First to God, then to men.
Again.
[Be a good reporter - first to God, then to men.]
I can't hear you!
Yes, first to God, then to men.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 26/02/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 03/03/2019